before our results before today
with a strong large deal and mega deal
wins we are building
well for the future
a pipeline to large deals is strong and
can and we continue to have mega deals
in our pipeline
we are delighted that topaz are Ai and
generative AI platform is resonating
well with our clients we are working on
80 generative AI projects for our
clients at this time
the work we are doing encompasses large
language models for software development
text document voice and video
internally we've developed generative AI
tools using an open source model for
software development
we are working with open source and
proprietary generative AI platforms and
models
we have trained 40 000 employees on
generated AI
we see opportunities for new work and
for productivity improvements through
this technology
all of these elements are available
within our profile set of capabilities
we see this area of generative Ai and
topaz the ingredient transformative for
our clients
as we look ahead with a large and
negative successes and our strength in
cost efficiency Automation and
consolidation we feel confident
in the short term we see some clients
stopping or slowing down work on
transformation programs and
distrustingly work
this is especially so in financial
services in mortgages Asset Management
Investment Banking and payments
and in the Telecom industry
we also see some impact in the high-tech
industry and in parts of retail
even as we won two Mega deals recently
and have a strong pipeline of large and
mega deals we receive revenue from some
of these and other large deals towards
the later part of our financial year
keeping that in mind we are changing our
Revenue growth guidance for this
financial year
the growth of one percent to three and a
half percent in constant currency
as a consequence of a mega deal wins
overall traction and cost efficiency
Automation and differentiated digital
cloud and generative AI capabilities
we are well positioned for the medium
term and especially towards the end of
our financial year and the period after
that
we've launched a broader and
comprehensive margin expansion program
the program will work across five areas
pyramid efficiency Automation and
generative AI improvements in critical
portfolios
reducing indirect costs and
communicating and deriving value across
the portfolio
our senior leadership is mobilized on
this we're working on this program with
our clients our employees and partners
and we're taking steps for the short
median and long term while keeping the
overall strategic Direction the company
in mind
we have an ambition to improve our
operating margin in the future periods
operating margin guidance for the
financial year remains unchanged at 20
to 22
with that let me hand it over to
milanjan
good evening everyone and thank you for
joining the call
we entered FY 24 in the backdrop of
uncertain
Maxwell economic environment with
clients reassessing the I.T sense and
continue to focus on cost and efficiency
programs q1 Revenue growth was 4.2
percent on a why on why basis in
constant currency sequentially revenue
is grew by one percent in constant
currency and 1.4 percent in dollar terms
operating margins of q1 was 20.8 percent
30 basis points lower sequencies this
works primarily due to a 70 basis point
of benefit from cost optimization
including utilization automation which
is offset by a balanced 90 basis point
in fact from employee related costs
including higher variable Pace
promotions Etc
client metrics remain strong with the
number of 50 million clients increasing
to 79 and 200 million dollar clients at
15. reflecting a strong ability to mine
stops clients by providing them multiple
multiple relevant Services head count at
the end of the quarters to that 336 000
employees which is a decline of two
percent from the previous quarter a
substantial portion of attrition has
been bachelored by training and
reskilling existing pool of talent and
deployment of pressures consequently our
utilization excluding trainees improved
to 81.1 percent which has further had
room for growth we will calibrate the
hiring for fi 24 based on available pool
of employees growth expectations with
electrician trends
Consolidated cash and equivalent so that
4.5 billion at the end of the quarter
this is before the payout of final
dividend that happened in the first week
of July EPS grew by 6.6 in dollar terms
and 12.4 percent in rupee terms we Loan
cash balance was 6.71 percent in q1
Roe increased to 32.8 percent in q1 or
1.8 increase year on year which is a
reflection of strong cash generation and
capital allocation policies largely
momentum continued and we signed 16
large zeros in q1 TCU of 2.3 billion
with 56 Net News three Deals each were
an fs eurf and communication four in
retail two in manufacturing one in life
science is vertical region-wise the soft
split by 11 in America or in Europe and
one in rows coming to Vertical segment
performance Financial Services vertical
which is continuous process in areas
like mortgage Asset Management
Investment Banking cards and payments
large and Super Regional banking clients
in U.S have been resilient during this
quarter large banking clients are
focusing on vendor consolidation cost
takeouts and self-funding transformation
programs many financial institutions are
looking at Outsourcing the non-core
business that includes taking over
existing employees across technology and
operations while delayed decision making
is impacting the vertical or recent deal
wins and the strong pipeline would help
create momentum and opportunities for
future growth in retail cost efficiency
and consolidation continue to remain top
priorities for our clients this there is
intense focus on leveraging AI to
accelerate digital transformation for
enhanced customer and employee
experience Predictive Analytics and
real-time insights while decision Cycles
are long will not be the pipelines
remain healthy in infra apps and process
modernization cloud and workload
migrations
communication sector is witnessing
continued impact from budget cuts to
delayed decision making for newer spends
and slow ramp UPS
cost optimizations and vendor
consolidation the top priority for
clients who open to innovative solutions
and are asking for AI to amplify
productivity OEM clients are showing
greater interest in Revenue generating
Services decrease time to markets
increase product quality and improved
customer experience largely pipeline in
this vertical remains very handy outlet
for the energy utilities resources and
services vertical continues to be
positive though they slow down in
decision making energy clients are
coming to us the large-scale
confirmation programs such as digital
capability for engine energy transition
and journey to Net Zero
utilities clients are focused on
in-flight transformation programs or
those required for Regulatory Compliance
service clients are focused on
consolidation and M A Cloud cost
optimization and Legacy transformation
our investment in Industry clouds and
Solutions in the energy transaction area
has helped us differentiate in these
sectors when multiple deals and build a
very strong pipeline manufacturing
clients are focusing on controlling
their spends and awarding these which
are focused on differentiations despite
the volatile environment deep pipeline
is strong areas like Engineering iot
Supply Chain Cloud Erp and digital are
seeing increased transactions there's a
need to increase space of migration to
Cloud increasing productivity by
transforming to Smart Factory and
transitioning to Smart products we are
seeing opportunities across Auto
Aerospace and Industrials we have
revised our Revenue growth guidance to
sr24 to 1 to 3.5 percent in constant
currency terms this is due to lower than
expected volumes due to ramp downs and
discrete stress spends coupled couple
coupled with lower Mega deal volumes
arising from delayed timing and longer
ramp up times due to regulatory
approvals and transitions margin
guidance remains at 20 to 22 for S5 24.
we continue to as far as I margins of
the media term it's a razor sharp focus
on cost optimization and efficiency
Improvement as someone mentioned we have
launched a new margin maximization
program as well as the Five Pillars
comprising over 20 tracks with that we
can open up the call for questions
thank you very much
we will now begin the question and
answers session
participants who wish to ask a question
may press star and one on their
testosterone telephone
if you're using a speakerphone please
pick up your handset while asking a
question
this is required to ensure Optimum core
audio quality on the call
should your line have any disturbance
you may be asked to return to the
question queue if you don't have a clear
connection
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles
the first question is from the line of
kavaljit saluja from kotak preschool
yeah hi uh thank you uh you know my
first question is the fact that I don't
prepare demands both the nanjan and both
of you mentioned that
the guidance cut is partly due to a
delay in volumes or other delay in
signings of Mega deals but as far as I
remember your guidance uh you know at
the lowering was not predicated at uh
you know not predicated on Mega
disclosure which is four percent and
seven percent was predicated on uh Mega
D's four years and volumes flowing
through so I'm just trying to understand
if you can just desire your guidance and
you know basically just highlight what
percentage of the cut is attributable to
your perception of change in view in the
external environment and what percentage
is really the you know debate signings
of Mega deals here
foreign
[Music]
of course was predicated a lot on the
base volumes uh which by default would
be in quarter one quarter two and this
is where we have seen this Christian
cuts uh in quarter one in some clients
uh and of course in Q2 as well some of
that softness continues uh and as you
know if you have to meet the year
quarter one and quarter two are very
critical uh uh for that really to happen
so fundamentally that's the base reason
as we exit the year
of course at the higher end there was
the impact of Mega deals uh and uh
guidance on both ends have come down and
one of the reasons the top end that has
come down is also largely also due to
the delay in mega deals signing and the
transition time but the pipeline at
Southern side is very healthy uh we've
got to under the belt and we are as
confident as we exit the year
but uh and imagine I'm just going to try
to know when he basically spoke in the
last quarter you did highlight that one
queue would be weak and you expect
pickup in two queue whereas right now
you're saying that uh you know 120q has
strong quarters I'm just trying to
understand the disconnecting commentary
uh the second part the element of the
question
is that you know two consecutive
quarters two consecutive misses I guess
last time around as well there's a lot
of pushback saying that the environment
has deteriorated and have you built in
any extra cushion into your guidance
Etc so what are your learnings uh you
know in those last two quarters and what
are the steps you have taken to ensure
that the forecasting process is a little
bit more robust than uh you know what
the guidance has the guidance cut is
asked to quarter indicate
when we get the guidance we see the
Outlook at that point of time we have a
semblance of what is a pipe we assume
some convertibility there's an existing
book of business uh but like I just said
in q1 from a sequential basis we are
lower than where we thought we would end
up to be right because like I said q1
and Q2 was critical for us to meet that
guidance and uh we have seen these
discretionary cuts uh in clients in some
sectors which we've just called out
right and that's what I would say the
base business and on the other side is
the Mega deal impact uh we've got a good
Pipeline and some of these deals which
were supposed to kick in earlier are
getting delayed later into the year as
we speak
uh okay uh uh okay uh that's uh clear uh
just a final comment here how's the
pipeline uh you know after the
conversion of the two billion dollars uh
uh you know as such and just comment on
the pipeline that'll be useful
uh so kaval this is salil uh the
pipeline uh we still have a good
pipeline of both large deals we have
some Mega deals in the pipeline as well
we see a lot of the work that we're
doing on cost on efficiency Automation
in consolidation and those are tracking
well with clients
there are some transformation programs
which are funded from within the cost
efficiency those are also uh something
that we're tracking through so we do see
with the two Mega deal sign a good
pipeline today of large deals and we
have mega deals in the pipeline as well
right and I understand you know is the
upper end of the guidance band in any
way uh predicated on future Mega
declusions of it's based on other days
closed uh you know up to now
see here the way we've built this
guidance or a view of the 3.5 is based
on what we have closed today in large
and mega deals and then we have a way of
estimating based on what we see into the
future uh as an aggregate not not as a
one-off or not as a binary discussion
but in aggregate with what we see as the
probabilities and also the probability
of when that work will transition and
the revenues are so those are what we
see in the pipeline are baked into it
thank you
the next question is from the line of
yogesh Agarwal from HSBC please go ahead
yeah hi thanks for letting me come uh
certainly this couple of questions uh
firstly on banking uh your banking uh
business has been there for few quarters
and now most other companies are showing
weakness as well uh whereas if you look
at the clients itself most of their
financial results the big commentaries
and the data is not that weak so where
is the disconnect uh you think are they
spending more with capitals or smaller
subcontractors uh where is this market
share loss coming from
uh yogesh I think what we see in our
financial services or banking uh part of
financial services there are different
clients awards that have different
patterns uh in terms of their own
pressures within their business some of
our clients have had good results but
there are some which have had more
difficult economic situations
also with a mix from geography between
Europe uh Asia Pacific and uh us
when you break it down into specific sub
industry areas where you look at Asset
Management when we look at Investment
Banking when you look at
payments or mortgages those are the ones
where they're seeing the impact our
sense is generally our clients
uh
not spending on those projects it's not
that they're spending somewhere else
typically they're choosing not to spend
at this time and as the environment
changes we will see how that pattern
changes
okay okay thanks and just a quick
follow-up uh you know very wise guidance
now uh at the lower end I wanted to ask
you you have already one few Mega deals
and the lower end of the guidance
suggests almost negative or flatish
growth for the next three quarters which
would have which would also mean that's
a six seven quarters now revenues would
be flat so so what are the assumptions
for the lower end of the guidance I
wanted to know
so yeah as the London was sharing about
the guidance the approach is really
focused on what we've seen in terms of
volumes discretionary projects uh in
quarter in q1 and
an overlay then of the actual Mega deals
and large deals we have already won and
and the estimate that we're looking at
so we are some of those deals have start
dates have moved out
whereas the volume and discretionary
project uh slowing is still in quarter
so
our view is based on how that plays out
between those Trends we saw the one
percent in terms of the lower end of the
guidance when you combine that and then
of course the higher end we talked about
earlier
thank you
the next question is from the line of
ankur rudra from JP Morgan please go out
thank you um Salon thank you for the
updated guidance I just wanted to get a
sense of you know obviously we ask great
for the next uh three quarters is now
moderated from maybe it could have been
two to four percent with the same old
guidance it's zero to one and a half as
discussed I'm just curious about the
discretionary cuts and the delays you
reference in your guidance change
description has this happened uh more
towards the latter half of the quarter
has there been a linear uh change over
the course of the quarter
we've seen it is uh
there will be no difference in the
pattern at the beginning or the end of
the quarter uh it's more focused on the
industry that we referenced in in our
opening remarks between the London and
me we have seen in different places the
discretionary work and some
transformation work where it was either
slowed or stop based on different
Industries
okay and you know also one just want to
get a sense of uh maybe asking this in a
slightly different way we obviously the
the guidance change is quite uh drastic
is this just the change in environment
of spending uh over the course of the
last three months or is this also a
difference in the way you measure the
likelihood of success of when the deals
ramp up or the win rate of future deals
are just curious about you know that and
if this guidance is is more conservative
in any way versus the last time you said
it
today
um it's it's a combination as you
pointed out of the environment in terms
of this history or transformational
projects in quarter
and then
some of the mega deals on large deals uh
we saw delay in decision making in
closing
and also delay or changes in the start
time or ramp up of the profile of that
business we've actually not seen any
change in the win rate and in fact
internally we had a good good win rate
in q1 and we continue to see a good
traction whether it's consolidation cost
efficiency on the win rate side
appreciate that just one clarification
if you could you know this two billion
dollar framework agreement that you
reference is your second large deal uh
could you clarify if this is uh fully
contracted and is this type of deal
historically also been disclosed in your
tcbs over the last few quarters or years
and there's really we have uh first made
the announcements as I'm sure you've
seen we have completed the contract uh
signing of the deal that's when the deal
was uh announced
these types of deals were also included
in the past within a large deal mix of
course in the past there was no uh
requirement of this closing the specific
values
okay I understood last question if I can
on margins uh they were obviously
flattest this time and you know it
doesn't I mean it seemed like you've
done well given what the growth has been
uh the Five Point margin maximization
plan you've highlighted is this uh you
playing offense or defense or margins in
other words is Infosys confident of
potentially expanding margins in f24 or
is it more for margin defense because
growth Outlook doesn't look very strong
at least at the lower end of guide
yeah so like we said I mean this is a
two-year program we have started uh it
is quite comprehensive uh it's just not
looking at Cost it's looking at uh
portfolio uh and this is now being led
uh personally by JS with uh 20 uh tracks
30 leaders of course our aspiration
continues to be that we will Aspire for
higher margins and where we are today so
uh I will provide that perspective it is
offensive on offense I was offensive but
on office uh this thing to increase our
margins that's the intent
appreciate it thank you investment
thank you
the next question is in the line of
apurva Prasad from HDFC Securities
please go ahead
yep uh thanks for taking my question uh
just want to prod further on the
guidance in the last quarter you had
referred to achieving proper basis the
strength of Pipeline and factors that
are binary
so are those binding factors still in
the pipeline uh or this converted the
transition is it's taking longer so what
I'm trying to get at is how should we
really reconcile the change in Revenue
guide in the last three months between
delay and volume cut switch which is as
large as 600 million
today
um
we've already announced two Mega these
so which is a positive we have large and
mega deals in the pipeline uh the way
we've seen it is really uh the two
points you mentioned which is the volume
discretionary work in quarter uh and the
delay in the start of the realization uh
transition of some of the large and mega
deals those are what have what have
translated to the change in the guidance
anyway that you could split those
factors how much of an interact would
that have been
uh we we will not be in a position to
quantify that further between those two
uh unfortunately
so uh okay and just uh how would you
characterize uh the business environment
and your client conversations at the end
of the quarter as compared to how it was
at the beginning of the quarter
so there it's it's uh really uh the way
we see it is
a pipeline for large and mega this is in
excellent shape as we close the quarter
we see good traction for uh Mega deals
and our large deals the focus is much
more when you're talking to clients on
efficiency of cost or consolidation we
have a real traction with them
we see less discussions on digital
transformation and then
in general across the client base for
those industries that are referenced in
the opening remarks we see whether this
crestory programs where the client feels
that they can slow them or pause them
for some time we see that action so so
those are the two sort of actions we're
seeing a very good Traction in fact on
the large magazines
a question
yes yes thanks
thank you
the next question is from the line of
Kumar Rakesh from BNP pariba please go
ahead
hi good evening thank you for taking me
a question uh my first question was more
of a clarification so can you just
confirm the process of deciding the
revenue growth guidance is it the same
which was last fiscal year versus this
year or have you changed some of the
assumptions or the processes that you
followed
following the same approach that we
followed over the last several years as
we build uh a sort of Outlook of our
guidance that we share with the market
thanks uh my second question was on the
Martin side so this quarter we had a
slight decline on the margin
sequentially now wage how it is yet
so how confident are you on holding on
to the current margin or the March
industry had last year when the cost
Living Program also that you are going
to start running or there would be more
of headwind Grant payments on the margin
site
as you saw my margin walk right we
actually had a 70 basis points uh
benefit uh from utilization cost
optimization so we are seeing the
Tailwinds of that and the big part of
that we've actually put back into
employee employee related compensation
which is uh variable pay that's a big
part promotion so it's not that we are
losing that to the market that's a
conscious decision for us to you know
plow it back towards our employees so as
we look ahead uh you know we are
actively considering uh compensation uh
hikes as well we transferred in our
press uh conference earlier
and the new program which kicks in uh we
think in optimization will give us a
necessary Tailwind uh to be uh you know
well within the margin guidance band
okay thanks for that my last question
was around the volume commentary which
you gave to last quarter in April when
we had the discussion you had talked
about that volume through the quarter
you were seeing signs of improvement
however in this quarter you have seen
performing much below your expectation
so what has written specific Pockets you
are seeing the weakness specifically is
it more slang specific or the entire
second industry you're asking a much
shorter weakness
it is a client specific uh uh like this
time in fact we saw slightly more
resilience in the U.S based clients
Europe turned out to be slightly uh
weaker uh so it is very client specific
actually uh across and you know it's uh
you know sort of a leaking bucket in uh
you know number of clients you know
there's no large uh sort of a drop-off
uh and this is ugly but I think that's
right the discretionary part right so it
is you know some programs you know which
can be pulled back and are discrete in
the nature those are the ones we are
seeing
thanks for that
thank you
the next question is from the line of
James stridelman from Sasuke Hana please
go ahead
hi thank you
um so we'll I think many investors are
wondering so I would appreciate your
thoughts
um does it seem to you that the soft
demand is primarily due to macro factors
which are presumably temporary or is it
potentially something more profound like
perhaps related to the relevance of
services or mind share so is this just
macro and it's going to go away or is it
a question of services itself
um so this is salil uh thanks for the
question the way we see it today uh we
see this this uh demand environment
especially on this history that we've
been discussing so far uh as a function
of the macro environment we can see for
example if you look at different
Industries manufacturing growing at 21
other Industries doing well whether
Financial Services weaker
so our service portfolio We Believe
works well we've already transformed the
company moved it predominant
predominantly into a digital business
and we are very strong on cloud with
that Cobalt offering now with generative
Ai and broadly with AI we've launched
our topaz offering my senses those are
resonating well with clients and the
places where we see the constraint have
been more with the macro even some of
the large and mega deals we're winning
we're winning against fairly intense
competition where we are demonstrating
our capabilities whether it's from
transformation or on cost or efficiency
or consolidation
okay thank you for that context cereal
I'll drop back in the cube
from nomura please go ahead
yeah thank you uh I have two questions
uh first of all Sally congrats to you
for this two billion dollar Mega deal uh
if you could share some more details you
know around this project given that it
is probably the largest you know
announced anywhere globally is it pure
Services deal or you know there is an
element of you know any hardware
purchase along with it and uh do you
think this will get into Revenue
translation mode in the second half of
this year
uh so thanks for the question uh on this
specific deal what we have shared in the
public domain is as per the filing with
the stock exchange it really focuses on
work that we're doing
related to Ai and automation-led
development modernization and
maintenance services
we don't have anything more to add to
that comment
sure do you think this goes into Revenue
translation second half
yeah so again there we don't have
anything more on the specific deal it's
more the general comments we talked
about the large and negative we do see
in general across our large and negative
uh uh the the the
revenue coming through in terms of the
Transitions and revenue realization more
towards the later part of the year
got it thank you thank you for that
you'll enjoyed my final second question
is to you now so you commented that you
know the salary Heights are under active
consideration so do you think this year
the hike cycle could differ you know
compared to our usual cycle
um and you know it could be more linked
to when the growth comes back we
probably will be in a more but you know
better position to get the high score
employees
so like I said we are considering
everything uh nothing to add more than
that really in terms of timing or
anything like that
okay got it thank you now the best
thank you
the next question is from the line of
Moshe katri from vet Bush Securities
please go ahead
thanks
um in general it seems that Europe has
been holding up really well
previously handset
you're not very clear yes
yes
um so so far Europe has really been
holding us well much better than the US
can you talk a bit about what you're
seeing in Europe maybe areas where you
are seeing some strengthens and the
verticals I'm assuming the UK is is a
big part of it and as that Trend
continues based on what you're saying
I.E is Europe still holding in there or
is it also slowing down that's my first
question thanks
uh so thanks for your question this is
salil we saw good traction and we've
seen that over the last several quarters
in Europe as you pointed out we've seen
that especially in the manufacturing
segment we've had good Traction in
multiple geographies in Europe so we've
had a good Traction in the nordics we
also announced a strategic win in the
nordics which was public a few weeks ago
we have good traction uh in uh Germany
as you reference a good Traction in UK
so we we've had uh
good traction so far now the macro
environment we see as as the London also
pointed uh earlier is definitely
something that is affecting overall in
Europe so we are seeing within the
segmentary reference for example
financial services and the sub segments
there uh in Telco
in some parts of retail those being
impacted in Europe as well and we'll see
how that plays out into the future
plan and my follow-up is about an
article that came out this week in the
local media in India suggesting that
there is an upset and demand for lateral
hires in the industry and these hires
will probably start happening in the you
know in the um in the month of October
and on
uh is that is that does that make sense
to you versus what you're seeing out
there in terms of demand and Pipeline
and the ramp that's kind of as you said
it's kind of slower than expected
so for us uh the the my sense is uh
again some of the comments you might
have heard earlier from the London our
utilization has gone up our total head
count number is reduced and we believe
we have some Headroom for the
utilization to go up further so that
that would be the context in in which we
are operating
understood thanks for the color
thank you the next question is from the
line of mukul Garg from motilal oswal
financial services please go ahead
yeah hi uh thanks
um just wanted to you know kind of probe
a bit further on the change in the
guidance and I'm just you know focusing
on the lower end of your previous
guidance
um I mean it does not look like the Miss
and q1 from you know what you guys kind
of thinking about last quarter was that
meaningful for the guidance at the lower
end to come down so drastically so is it
fair to assume that uh you know the
incremental slowdown which you have
witnessed is more uh front-ended IE in
Q2 or was there an expectation uh of a
you know meaningful pickup uh in the
business in second half which is now no
longer there
so on the guidance uh again some of the
comments uh that milanjan shared earlier
we saw
in q1
the volume and the stationary projects
slowing
and based on that class the delay in
some of the large Omega deals
starting up in terms of Revenue we felt
uh that that would that has given us the
view of the lower end of the guidance
what we see really the function of the
way the volume and the stationary
project evolves the macro environment as
we look out
is changing as we see things which are
from U.S to Europe to Asia keeping those
those factors in mind is how we built
that lower end of the guidance
sure and uh you know and similarly on on
similar track uh you know is there uh
you know something we need to kind of
see visualize in terms of sanctity of
large dltc which we disclose uh your
commentary on Pipeline and large deal
wins continues to remain very robust but
uh there is a fair bit of pain which you
are kind of talking about from a
discussionist side which would be coming
out of the large deal number so you know
can you share the impact on overall tcv
or is that something you know which you
would kind of start reassessing uh
simply because it's giving a leading
picture when you look at only the last
reason
so they uh there are sort of some
distinctions what we are seeing in the
large these Mega deals wins uh
in the pipeline and what's more recent
in the past quarters was more on cost or
efficiency of consolidation
and so that work is continuing what we
reference on the Slowdown is more on
discretionary projects which are
projects or transformation projects
which are from before which could have
been paused or slowed down by the client
and specifically in the industries where
we reference the impact those are the
ones we are seeing so they're not in a
sense correlated with the last days that
we're looking at today
sure and information
in terms of your growth guidance from
any client specific issue uh you know
specifically uh as well engine kind of
highlighted in Europe in terms of client
in sourcing or uh you know kind of
slowing down uh business to you in any
vertical
so there uh What uh referencing to is
not that it is plan specific as in a one
or two climb it was more in terms of
clients within that industry industry
vertical and more now shifting uh
uh you know what we had in the U.S to
the European market so it is not that we
have a specific one or two clients where
we've seen uh this impact showing up
from them
sure I think that's helpful thanks for
taking my question
thank you
the next question is from the line of
Surendra goes from Citigroup please go
ahead
good evening so I know that you don't
share this data point but could you give
us a directional sense of how ACV
analyze contract where you friends would
have moved or would compare yui given
the changing nature of these towards the
large and mega cost accounting
uh thanks for the questions surender we
are not in a position to share that
information
okay and on this recently announced uh
uh the one that was announced after the
quarter before the results
oh yeah yes yes
okay so again we are not announcing the
net new in a specific deal what I
mentioned earlier was the type of work
and that that's what we can say in
addition to what we find with the stock
exchange
sure thank them
thank you
the next question is from the line of
Prashant kothari from Victor please go
ahead
when looking at the revenue growth
guidance this year it seems you'll be
growing maybe uh worse than the uh peer
group that that we track even in terms
of the deciding on management
composition how do we think about that I
mean are there uh things that we need to
do in order to regain the uh kind of
competitiveness in the market so we can
continue to outgrow out there or or you
think it's all down down to
discretionary demand being weak and
therefore there's nothing much that you
can do um and we just need to wait for
the cycle to come back
um that's the first question
so there um we
have a view with our portfolio that it's
a portfolio of services that works well
with our clients we absolutely uh have
the intensity in the client environment
with a large and mega deal wins to be
back into the growth uh mode that within
uh in for the last several years we also
have uh as you know a high base for
comms uh q1 of last year was 21
growth a year and year on the previous
year
whereas the the
environment of the other peers were not
there so all of those factors coming
into play we are very much of the view
that we have uh what we need and they
continue to go into new areas like
generative AI or continue investments in
Cloud to build out what we want what our
clients are looking for to continue with
the growth situation
okay thank you so if it is kind of more
about the external environment then uh
what would be a good kind of a leading
indicator that you would use have
internally uh to figure out this this
weak discretionary demand phrases kind
of coming to an end
so in generally we have several uh
elements we look at these are not
typically uh the data we share uh
externally but in terms of the overall
sort of translation of that is what we
translate into the guidance and
all right yeah which is presenting a bit
of a weak picture as of now all right
okay thank you
thank you
everyone please go ahead
hi good evening thank you I wanted to
ask on the margin expansion program so I
understand this is a two-year initiative
can you give us a sense of materiality
just how are you thinking about the
potential cost savings or an approximate
margin expansion potential that you
expect to achieve from these pillars
uh pricing and a more holistic you know
sort of value-based selling uh approach
uh that's a big one uh are we know from
a it's in a pyramid perspective uh we
have a lot of scope uh as well we
understand the generative Ai and our
ongoing automation uh projects which we
have that's you know continuously and
actually with generative AI we think we
can up productivity from uh Baseline
even more some of our portfolios uh in
our mix how do we improve uh you know
margins that to a dedicated you know
head team looking at these accounts and
finally the indirect cost side and how
do we keep the cap on that looking at
more efficient buying procurement uh
savings Etc so it's a quite a holistic
approach like I said across 20 tracks uh
and these have been ticked off uh can't
quantify the you know number at this
stage but like we said aspiration
continues to be to improve our margins
in the medium levels
okay and then my follow-up understanding
you've gotten a lot of questions here on
on the fiscal 24 growth Outlook just
trying to clarify everything here in
energy tile all these questions together
is it right to say that at the low end
of your 24 growth guidance that you're
assuming a worsening of volume
reductions and a worsening of
decision-making pace for the balance of
the year
and then at the upper end that the
decision making improves just trying to
really get to the point of are you
assuming more of the same in the
Improvement or further deterioration
within this range
um there the way we've constructed this
uh guidance
we see that there is a change or a
difference in the environment in the
decision making uh we have seen some of
the impact in some of the industries
that I uh that we shared earlier and we
will see
how that volume discretionary work
translates itself over time so we've
baked in some range of possibilities
into that we want to see how those
possibilities play out
thank you
the next question is from the line of
nitin padmanaban from investec please go
ahead
yeah hi uh good evening time for the
opportunity uh so uh
the employee head count is down uh three
percent over the last two quarters
but the absolute employee cost is up two
percent so what explains that dynamic
time we have put about you know 90 bips
I think of impact you won't see the
entire thing in employee cost
uh because even third party costs have
come down but if you see about 90 uh
basis points actually more than 120 and
then 90 basis points is actually in
employee costs the variable pay is a big
one which we have upped uh constantly in
this quarter a little bit of promotion
than the other other items balancing
items yeah so uh this is the
clarification there so uh so in the
context of the deteriorating environment
and attrition sort of falling uh the
Assumption was that employee costs would
be something relatively easier to manage
uh and obviously because the performance
company-wide performance itself is lower
uh the variable also should be lower so
what's driving the dynamic on higher
variable pay and the compensation
because we look at this holistically I
think I mean we are I mean you don't
look at this one quarter and decide uh
these decisions we're looking at the
overall environment uh and you know uh
attrition Etc and that's a decision we
collectively take it's just not you know
quarter to quarter basis uh we have
enough Headroom in our utilization uh to
grow uh volumes and uh therefore the
attrition which we see uh is not
entirely replaced by lateral hiring a
part of that happens through lateral
hiring and we continue to reskill and
move up our pressure bench and rotate
people through projects so that benefit
we continue to get and like I said the
you know 70 bits benefit which we are
seeing is coming partly because of
improved utilization right
sure and uh lastly uh the 2.1 billion
dollar deal that we announced uh in
which vertical is that it's a good class
that'll be helpful
uh no we don't mention that uh really on
what vertical is okay thank you so much
and all the very best
thank you thank you
the next question is from the line of
Weber singer from novama equities please
go ahead
just wanted to understand uh the putting
on hold of this stationary spend and
other issues that you mentioned that
caused us to lower this guidance uh do
you see that as a very Infosys specific
thing or do you see it more of an
industry across the board that maybe
other companies are not seeing it right
now they might be following suit in
London's next few quarters or is it some
something in the nature of our portfolio
because of which you probably feel that
it was a stick because I think in the
last three months of the other companies
that are reported they might not have
been searching of the difference in the
uh
guidances but the kind of situent or
after that you have seen we haven't seen
that kind of a change in commentary over
the past three months by any other
players are safe so would you like to
basically give some color on how
readable is this uh environment that has
caused us for this iteration to the
other companies in the sector of the
industry
so there
um
my sense is uh if you look at our q1
number we have one percent quarter on
quarter growth which from what I have
seen across the industry is maybe one of
the strongest quarter and quarter growth
uh we have a clear view of what what we
see as we've been discussing on large
and mega deals giving us a strong growth
orientation later in the year
with some discretionary work which is uh
slowing in in q1 so I don't have a sense
for for the other uh players but that's
how we see it and if I look at q1 we
have a good outcome in terms of a solid
quarter uh and and looking at the
industry maybe a higher growth Q on Q
than than many others
I think you mentioned it before in the
call as well uh I mean I mean uh how uh
I mean what is the overall General
conversation like when they put this
this stationary part of the lease on
hold I mean do they want to do it given
the weak matro at this point of time is
there any rethinking on the part or
whether they need this kind of uh spend
at all are those uh original decisions
uh being questioned itself to begin with
what exactly is the nature of the
conversation with the clients which are
putting these uh spends on board
in general uh what we've seen is again
in the industries we reference before
whether it's Financial Services or Telco
or high tech like clients or the
industries are going through a difficult
environment themselves in the macro
they're looking for help or support from
their Partners like us where they put
some projects which they perceive to be
not immediately relevant for them uh on
a pause or slowing those are the
discussionary works that slow down and
we will see uh as the environment
changes what happens
thank you
ladies and gentlemen that would be our
last question for today I now had a
conference packed with the management
for the closing remarks thank you and
over to you
thanks uh Elizabeth I just want to close
out uh thank you everyone for joining us
uh in summary for us really we've had a
solid q1 very good Q on Q growth solid
margins excellent large deals and mega
deals uh wins this sets us up very
nicely with some of the delays and the
volume slowing more for the later part
of the year we've also got incredible
Traction in generative AI with ap
projects and and the topaz work
resonating with clients we've now put in
place a stronger program on margin
expansion which is in play putting all
of that together
we see this is a year where we make that
difference translating to negatives and
large deals and as we come towards the
later part of the Year showing the
realization realization of all of those
so thanks again everyone for joining in
and look forward to catching up at the
next what we call this
thank you very much members of the
management
ladies and gentlemen on behalf of
Infosys that concludes this conference
thank you all for joining us and you may
now disconnect your lines